Valentin Fernandez Radovich

Data Scientist & ML/AI Engineer

fernandezradovich@gmail.com | +5492236694448 | Buenos Aires, Argentina | LinkedIn | GitHub | Medium | Portfolio

ABOUT ME

Specialized in AI and ML Engineering with background in Software Development.

Data-driven software solutions enthusiast, a continuous learner and admirer of the latest technologies. You can read about my work on Medium or LinkedIn, let's connect!

EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist KL Labs • Self-employed 09/2023 - Present | Argentina

- Led a team in developing data driven end-to-end solutions: Full model training, test, evaluation and deploy with Tensorflow, utilizing LSTM (RNN) in deep learning for time series forecasting. Predictive Models. Hugging Face Transformers for Sentiment Analysis. RAG applications and more NLP projects.
- Conducted extensive ETL processes from diverse data sources, such as API endpoints, Databases and extensive CSV Files.
- Executed comprehensive feature engineering, transforming time, text, and numerical data for model input.
- Leveraged Hugging Face Transformers for NLP tasks, extracting actionable insights from the results.
- Analyzed government events through data analytics and visualization techniques.
- Developed APIs and deployed them with Docker and GCP services.
- Utilized data visualization tools to effectively communicate findings to non-technical audiences.
- Demonstrated proficiency in data engineering, including project architecture design and cloud deployment using Google Cloud Platform.

Co-Founder

KL Labs • Self-employed

09/2023 - Present | Buenos Aires, Argentina

- · Established the company's mission and path.
- Managed data-driven projects and product development.
- Conducted market research and analyzed trends to make decisions.

Brand Image & Product Strategist Estudio47 • Full-time

03/2020 - 07/2023 | Mar del Plata, Buenos Aires, Argentina

- End to end designed and implemented product launches, with their respective labels, advertising, photography, marketing, social media flyers, website integration and layout.
- Turned those products into the company's best sellers.
- · Rebranded the brand on all commercial fronts.

Ski Cashier

Wintergreen Resort • Seasonal

12/2022 - 04/2023 | Nellysford, Virginia, United States

- · Sold lift tickets and rental equipments to visitors.
- Provided general resort information and instructions to all guests.

EDUCATION

Data Science & Al Bootcamp Le Wagon

07/2023 - 09/2023 | Remote (400 hours)

- Coursework: Data Cleaning and Preprocessing, Feature Engineering, Analytics, Statistical Analysis, Data Visualization, Decision Science, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Cloud Computing and Natural Language Processing.
- 9-week full-time (400hs) bootcamp using real data and projects works.

Programming Technical Degree, Software Engineering National Technological University 02/2020 - 12/2022 | Argentina

 Relevant Coursework: Object-Oriented Programming, Operating Systems, Computer Systems, Statistics, Mathematics, Business Organization, Algorithms, Web and Application Design, Databases, Software Development.

SKILLS

Database Managment Preprocessing
Feature Engineering Data Analysis
Deep Learning Machine Learning
Predictive and Forecasting Models
Artificial Intelligence NLP MLOps
Data Visualization Data Engineering

TECHNOLOGIES

Python SQL Git Numpy **Matplotlib Pandas Statsmodels Tensorflow** Seaborn Scikit-Learn LangChain Keras Transformers **LLMs OpenAl Docker MLFlow** FastAPI Streamlit Java C

LANGUAGES

Spanish English